Daniel Kamins

7853 Balson Ave Saint Louis MO 63130| (314)322-2865 | dkamins314@gmail.com

Experienced Educator and Editor

Objective

Analytical, insightful and mature programmer eager to help solidify a positive working environment in coding and computer related technologies.

Skills & Abilities

Management

Strengths:

Convey messages clearly, listen to input, and incorporate ideas that help others take ownership in a project.

Approach in working with people:

Help associates develop an attitude of self-respect for who they are, appreciation for what they have done and for their potential, and the belief that they are capable of producing at a high level.

Programing – Problem solving

My background in teaching and Talmudic Law means that I am constantly learning new approaches to problem solving; I have spent most of my life analyzing issues, in depth, from multiple angles, in order to develop appropriate solutions. I look forward to the challenging experiences that play major roles in expanding and enhancing my coding skills. I've worked with Python, HTML, CSS, Flask, MySQL, C#, and .NET Core.

Communication

As part of my teaching and rabbinical duties, my responsibilities included working with groups of all ages, to help them attain their goals. Communication is one of my stronger skills, especially written communication.

Leadership

As a teacher and a Rabbi, inspiring personal growth and commitment was fundamental. I am accustomed to setting, expressing and explaining goals.

Education

- · Completed LC101 coding at Launch Code -Saint Louis Mo. Dec 2018
- · Rabbinic Ordination Rabbinical College of Telshe, Wickliffe, Ohio 1985
- · Teaching Certification Kaufman Pedagogical Inst, Division of Telshe Rabbinical College 1984

References available upon request

Experience

- · Editor Chinuch.org (Website for teachers in Jewish Day Schools material sharing) 2011-Present Responsible for maintaining accuracy and professionalism requirements for submitted materials
- Home loan mortgage processing Coral Bank, American Mortgage Flagstar Mortgage MD Mortgage
 2001-2010

Responsible for preparing and submitting completed files to underwriting, clearing conditions

- Rabbi Beth Hamedrash Hagadol Congregation 1996-2006
 Responsible for weekly and Holiday services, regular sermons, congregational needs end of life guidance and service
- Teacher Jewish Day schools: Cleveland (1980-1985), Boston (1985-1989), Saint Louis (1989-2001)

 Responsible for teaching Hebrew reading, Bible, Prophets, Jewish law, Mishna, Talmud studies for primary grades (1-8)